A creative and skilful UI developer with experience designing and developing responsive and usercentric websites. Proficient in HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, MUI, BEM Methodology, Email templates and other web development tools. Good problem-solving skills and a passion for creating visually appealing and functional websites. Excellent communication and teamwork abilities.

Skills

Frontend UI Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, MUI.

Figma/Adobe XD/Sketch/Invision/PSD/design to HTML conversion.

Responsive UI development with cross-browser/device compatibility check.

Custom UIs tailored to client's specific needs and requirements.

Effective solution for UI/UX feasibility on the front end.

Support for change requests.

Collaboration with the design team and support for teammates.

Agile methodology and daily scrum.

Git for keeping source code.

Experience

HTML DEVELOPER, XLONGEVITY CHIRAYU PVT LTD - JUL 2023 - APR 2024

xLongevity is a Science-based longevity solution designed to support healthy ageing.

Coaching portal - https://web.xlongevity.com Website - https://www.xlongevity.com

Wrote responsive CSS-in-JS for UI components as per design from Figma file.

Followed MUI and Typescript coding conventions.

SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, VALUECODERS SERVICES LLP (A VINOVE COMPANY) - DEC 2021 - MAY 2023

Worked for their client FE Fundinfo (Domain: Finance) and

Created PDF themes for their European clients using HTML5, CSS3, CSS grid, CSS flexbox etc.

Did responsive UI development for their web pages and financial URLs.

Provided support to fellow team members for UI issues.

Tools used: Microsoft Azure DevOps, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Storage Explorer, PDF Reactor, theme generator etc.

Worked for their client named Flydocs India Pvt Ltd (Domain: Aviation).

Did responsive UI development for their Maintenance Control Centre module and classic Flydocs version.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, APPSTER LLP – DEC 2014 - DEC 2018

Revamped the entire frontend of apppster.com.au and appsterhq.com from scratch with two of my colleagues and implemented animations and plugins using CSS3, ¡Query and JavaScript.

Won QIII-Platinum Club 2016 for best project.

Collaborated with graphic designers and backend developers for the best UX.

Implemented responsive and mobile-friendly web interfaces for their clients.

Provided ongoing support and maintenance for websites post-launch.

Followed agile development and daily scrum.

Addressed client's feedback on basecamp and JIRA.

DESIGNER, CONVERGENT TECHNOLOGES - MAR 2014 - DEC 2014

Worked for their clients named Samsung, Apple, Eicher and NIIT.

Created banners and background images for special events and holidays.

Provided support to backend developers for UI integration.

Created designs for their CMS and converted them into HTML.

WEB DESIGNER, SAGACIOUS SOFTWARES(NOW DIGITAL HIVE) - AUG 2013 - MAR 2014

Designed websites using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.

Converted PSDs and designs into HTML for clients.

Used Bootstrap framework, and jQuery for plugin integration.

Helped fellow web designer with UI implementation.

UI DESIGNER, WEBREINVENT TECHNOLOGES PVT LTD - AUG 2012 - JUL 2013

Learned HTML, and CSS and started working on projects.

Learned Adobe Products like Photoshop and Illustrator for websites and logo design.

Started using jQuery for sliders and plugins.

Collaborated with clients to understand their vision and goals for the website and translated them into functional designs.

Worked on different projects with short deadlines.

Education

De Montfort University, Leicester, UK - MSc Information Technology - 2011 Institute of Technology & Management, Gurgaon - BE Electronics and Communications - 2008

Certificate

Namaste React Live Course TQVWC0AD - Feb 2023

Html Css Projects

xLongevity https://web.xlongevity.com

Windmill test task https://link2pk.github.io/windmill-test-task/

Flydocs https://beta.flydocsuat.com/

ANIA MANAGEMENT https://www.aniamanagement.com/

Cosmic Byte https://www.thecosmicbyte.com/

Savvy https://savvyapp.com.au/

Open Charity https://link2pk.github.io/open-charity

Ebill https://link2pk.github.io/ebill

ABCBank https://link2pk.github.io/ABCBank

International https://link2pk.github.io/international

Fitness Time https://link2pk.github.io/fitness-time

Six8 https://app.six8.com.au

ConsultThompson http://www.consultthompson.com

RMR Marmo https://www.rmrmarmo.com

Final Call https://www.finalcall.com.au

Streamhear http://www.streamhear.com

React Projects

Food Villa (Online food ordering App) https://link2pk.netlify.app/

Features: Restaurant listing, Restaurant Menu Items Listing, Search bar, User Online Status and Cart Functionality using Redux Toolkit. https://github.com/link2pk/namaste-react

Video Streaming App https://link2pkyt2.netlify.app/

Features: Videos Listing, Video Watch Page, Video Info and Description and Related video listing using Google Youtube APIs. https://github.com/link2pk/youtube2